Alice Richardson

Lady Lake, Florida | 970-817-1904 | Alice.richardson.dev@gmail.com | LinkedIn | Portfolio | GitHub | Blog

SUMMARY

I am a **Frontend Developer** with extensive experience and a bachelor's degree in design. I have completed the Full Stack Development Immersive Program from Flatiron school. I have a keen eye for the visual aspect of user experience and a strong desire to learn and create. I firmly believe in lifelong learning, and I'm constantly exploring new ideas and technologies. Having experience in both design and development, I am confident in my ability to create the most optimal user experiences.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

HTML, CSS, Javascript, React, Vue, React Native, Bootstrap, Material-UI, Node, Express, Ruby on Rails, MongoDB

GENERAL SKILLS / API INTEGRATION

UX and UI Design, Figma, Photoshop, Illustrator, Public API, Git, Github, Responsive Website, Customer Service

WORK EXPERIENCE

Zaronology Inc. | Jr. Web Application Developer

July 2021 - Present

- -Bringing mock-ups to life using HTML, CSS, Javascript.
- -Creating new features, functionality, and capabilities on the eCommerce sites.
- -Creating modular, responsive templates using modern CSS techniques and Javascript libraries.
- -Implementing a mobile-first approach to existing websites.

Food Haven Technologies Inc. | Software Engineer | Intern

May 2021- July 2021

- -Main focus Frontend building websites and apps, using **React** and React Native.
- -Testing to identify bugs and technical issues before and after deploying.
- -Maintaining an organized workflow using a project management tool (like GitHub)

Chim Media | Frontend Engineer | UX & UI Designer | Intern

Feb 2021 - May 2021

- -Design frontend webpage, integrate with public API
- -Working with in a team developing frontend, backend, and UX / UI

TECHNICAL PROJECTS

Thai Alphabet Flashcards // HTML | CSS | Javascript | Ruby | Rails - Github | Demo

Web application helps learning Thai language, with a mix-and-match game

- Made a mix-and-match memorization game with a time

limit and dynamic scoring using Javascript

- Designed clean and simple UI/UX for a focused learning experience
- Included audible readouts of letters to aid the visual impair

Ecofreak // Vue | Node | Express | MongoDB - Github | Demo

Web application to inspire environmentally safe practices, and learn how to lessen one's environmental footprint

- Created and styled frontend with Vue and Material design for bootstrap
- Built collaborative blog interface for users to share and contribute ideas to better help the world
- Created own API to allow users to save directly to a database

Parking Spot Finder // React-native | Ruby | Rails | AsyncStorage - Github | Demo

Mobile application to help users find a parking spot near their current location or destination

- Created a secure login using JSON web Tokens and AsyncStorage
- Enabled seamless mobile iOS and Android UX via React Native and Expo
- Integrated Google Maps API and Google Places API to locate users by longitude and latitude

VOLUNTEER EXPERIENCE

- Speaker at Women Who Code Boulder/Denver Monthly Meetup Video

EDUCATION

Flatiron School

Jan 2020 - May 2020 | Denver, CO

Full Stack Web Development, Ruby on Rails, and JavaScript Immersive Program

Bangkok University

Feb 2011 - Apr 2014 | Bangkok, Thailand

B.A. Architectural Interior Design | Minor in Architecture